Guide to the Democratic Socialists of America Records TAM.105
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series XII: Unprocessed
  - Records: About half the box contains Youth Section correspondence, 1976-1982; there are files from the 1979 convention in Houston; four thick files labeled "non-correspondence" contain national office administrative records, including circular letters, minutes and reports, and a few untitled typescripts, possibly by Harrington, and miscellaneous files, including "Tom Kahn and S.D. Criticism of DSOC Nuclear Policy," and "Dechartering of Miami Local (Box 7)
  - Records: Michael Harrington Writings and Travel / Speaking Engagements Correspondence; Miscellaneous Administrative Records and Subject Files. Includes Harrington typescripts: "Two Cheers for the 80s" and "Defining and Defending the Public Interest" and a few untitled Harrington typescripts, 1976-1981 (Box 8)
  - Records: Includes Minutes (national-level), 1979 Convention (Houston), five thick files "Biographical Information on Members"; two thick files from the 1981 Search Committee (for a National Director); files on various committee, projects and topics, including one thick file on Democratic Agenda (DSA's initiative within the Democratic Party), 1974-1982 (Box 9)
  - Records: About half the box contains folders labeled "non-correspondence" which contain administrative records, mostly from 1980-1981 (circulars, corespondence, reports, contact lists, printed ephemera, some concerned with the allied Institute for Democratic Socialism); there is also one small folder of Harrington correspondence (1981), and two folders, titled, respectively, "Harrington-Robert Bleiberg Debate (1977), and "Harrington, DSOC and the Social Democrats", 1970s-1980s (Box 10)
  - Records: General Correspondence (National Office), May 1978-Jan 1988 (Box 11)
  - Records: Youth Section Correspondence, Feb 1977-Jan 1988 (Box 11A)
  - Records: People's Power Project (Public, other energy program), 1975-76; Chapter files, mostly laphabetical by City, including publications, 1977-79; one thick file of New American Movement reports, 1977-78., 1975-1979 (Box 12)
  - Records: Democratic Agenda, 1976-80, 1976-1980 (Box 12A)
  - Records: Democratic Agenda, 1975-76, 1975-1976 (Box 12B)
  - Records: Key List Mailings, 1973-78; National Office Committee Minutes, 1979; Natioal Board Minutes, May 1979; DSOC direrctory and questionnaires, 1978-79 (one file)., 1973-1979 (Box 12C1)
  - Records: Conventions: 1975, 1977; National Executive Committee, 1979; Institute for Socialist Organizers, June 1975; Conference, Jan 1976. (Box 12C2)
  - Records: National Board, 1973-80, including 1973 elections; Feminist Commission, 1978-79; Internal Discussion (1 thick file, 1976); Ad[vertising] Council, 1973-1980 (Box 12)
  - Records: Convention, 1981, including discussion of merger with NAM; bulk of box pertains to Democratic Party, its 1980 convention, and Edward Kennedy's campaign for the presidential nomination, 1980-1981 (Box 12E)
  - Records: bulk of box pertains to Democratic Agenda, 1977-78, and related topical files'; several files of genral correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 12)
  - Records: Democratic Agenda - Democratic Party, 1976, 1976-1976 (Box 12G)
  - Records: DSOC Local and Regional Files - Alabama -- New York, 1975-1979 (Box 13)
  - Records: Other Organizations and Publications Files (labor and left), Topical Files, mostly beginning with the letters I---T, several like files beginning with the letter A., 1975-1979 (Box 13A)
  - Records: About one-third of the box consists of untitled folders of National Office materials, including circulars, correspondence, position papers and reports, much concerned with activity within the Democratic Party, including Democratic Agenda; the remainder of the box consists of files on organizations arranged alphabetically, American--Committee, including a thick file on Breira: A Project of Concern in Diaspora-Israeli Relations., 1975-1980 (Box 13B)
  - Records: The first third of the box consists of files on organizations, arranged alphabetically, Congress--Indians; several miscellaneous files relating to New York City area issues; with the last half of the box containing files on college and university chapters, the majority in New York State, but also including schools in Texas through Virginia and several other schools., 1974-1989 (Box 14)
  - Records: Includes several thick files from the formative years, 1972-93, including material from Socialist Party-Democratic Socialist Federation, Social Democrats, USA (and response to Harrington's resignation therefrom); several thick files of early DSOC administrative records, 1974--, with some writings, possibly by Harrington; DSOC State level organization files for states beginning with "A"; a file containing contact information for key people for chapters around the country; and several organizational and topical files, the latter chiefly relating to economic issues, such as full employment, 1972-1978 (Box 15)
  - Records: Includes a file on the State of California, and files on states Oklahoma--Wyoming; these files chiefly contain correspondence with / from the national office, and the most frequent correspondent is Jack Clark, with some correspondence of Harrington also present. Note that this box is only 0.5 linear ft., ca. 1974-ca. 1979 (Box 15A)
  - Records: Includes State and Chapter files, including local newsletters, Pennsylvania--Tennessee; several California chapters' files; two files of minutes: one from the Dec, 1987 Executive Committee, the other from the May 1988 National Executive Committee; miscellaneous national administrative files, and two files from the Youth Section, 1983-1988 (Box 16)
  - Records: Chiefly contains files of various NY State Chapters, including publications, from the 1980s; one thick file of national administrative materials ca. 1984; several files on the Local Development Func, 1991-1993, 1980-1993 (Box 17)
  - Records: Includes one thick file of Carl Shier correspondence, 1972-74; State chapters' files from the majority of letters in the alphabet, 1973-75; one file from the founding period of 1972-73 contining materials from DSOC's predecessor organizations; a file of undated ballots for National Board membership; and several Local Development project files, 1991-92., Bulk, 1972-1975 1972-1992; 1972-1975 (Box 17A)
  - Records: The bulk of the box consists of State chapters' files from Iowa--Montana, including local publications, 1984-1988; a file on an October, 1981 meeting on national priorities; and several files on the Local Development project, early 1990s., 1981-1991 (Box 18)
  - Records: State chapter files, Oregon--Wyoming, early-mid 1980s; several files of minutes of the National Organizing/Executive Com mittee[s]; a file from a Young Socialist Executive Committee meeting, 1990; Local Development Fund Files; a think file of administrative materials from 1981, including some Harrington circular letters; several DSA Commission files, including Anti-Racism, from 1994, 1981-1994 (Box 18A)
  - Records: Incomplete National administrative records, including Executive Committee minutes, 1980s-early 1990s; several files on the periodical Socialist Forum; and several Local Development project files., 1980-1992 (Box 19)
  - Records: DSOC national administrative files, ca. 1976-81, including several files of meeting minutes, a Newsletter of the Democratic Left Search Committee file, Personnel and Management Commitee, circulars and reports, surveys of locals; in addition there are several files for California chapters, for cities beginning with the letter "S", from the latter 1980s., 1976-1987 (Box 20)
  - Records: Minutes of the variously titled National Executive Committee, 1978-1992; one thick files "DSOC/DL" containing a computer printout of what may be a combined membership/subscriber list from 1980; and one file containing an address to the National Board of DSA by Michael Harrington, February, 1983. (Box 20A)
  - Records: Chapter files from New York--Texas, mid-late 1980s, including newsletters; several thick files of miscellaneous materials, most printed ephemera or periodicals of other organizations., ca. 1979-ca. 1988 (Box 21)
  - Records: Regional and local bulletins, 1973-75 (2 files); Chapter files, 1980s, for states from California--Pennsylvania, including publications; severl thick files of miscellaneous materials, some administrative, most printed ephemera and publications of other organizations, 1973-ca. 1988 (Box 21A)
  - Records: Two bound volumes of handwritten National Office Committee minutes, 1973-74; National Executive Committee minutes, 1985-88; one thick file on the New York Labor Forum, 1976; one folder with a letter to MH from John Kenneth Galbraith, Jul 1, 1975; and several topical files, 1973-1988 (Box 22)
  - Records: About half the box consists of National Executive Committee minutes, 1985-88; two thick files from 1978-79 containing correspondence, much pertaining to the Newsletter of the Democratic Left; a thick envelope containing hundreds of membership cards (undated); and miscellaneous printed ephemera., 1978-1988 (Box 23)
  - Records: Minutes, 1984-90 from the variously titled National Executive Committee and the National Board - included are various reports; there are also several files of materials received from the Democratic Party., 1984-1990 (Box 23A)
  - Records: National Board, 1987-92, 1987-1992 (Box 24)
  - Records: Chicago Red Squad Files on the New American Movement, 1971-74, 1971-1974 (Box 24A)
  - Records: The bulk of the material is from the 1987 convention, with a few files from the 1985 convention; a thick file of administrative material titled "Jimmy Higgins"; miscellaneous printed ephemera, ca. 1981-1987 (Box 25)
  - Records: Mostly 1991 convention; also several files on 1983 and 1984 "Conferences"; two files on the Youth Section (1980, 83); several topical files, 1980-1991 (Box 26)
  - Records: Youth Secton files, 1981-85; also several files of publications and printed ephemera, 1981-1985 (Box 27)
  - Records: Socialist International, 1976-80; Bylaws, 1989; Labor Commission, 1991, 1976-1991 (Box 27A1)
  - Records: Socialist International, 1972, 1979, 1983 (Box 27A2)
  - Records: Youth Section Winter Conferences, 1987-90; YS Keylist Mailings, 1980-81; Othe YS materials; Several National Board/Executive Committe meetings, latter 1980s; several folders of loose miscellaneous administrative records and ephemera, including a small amount of Harrington correspondence, 1980-1990 (Box 28)
  - Records: Youth Section, 1980-88: chapter, charters, minutes, reports, publications, including Days of Decision, job search for national director; One file "Past Speaking Dates [Harrington]", including MH correspondence., 1980-1988 (Box 29)
  - Records: Various administrative records and topical files, 1980-88, including 1980 leadership retreat; Youth Section records, 1980s, including search for national director, and several issues of Days of Decision; file on Billy Bragg tour, 1988, file on University in Society Project, 1986; note: last box in CS aisle 27, 1980-1988 (Box 29A)
  - Records: Records: About half the box is devoted to student activism (peace, against cuts in funding for educational and social programs, e.g. Student Alliance for an Immediate Freeze); one file on Harrington speaking engagements, invitations, etc., but little or no letters by MN; one thick file on anti-apartheid activity; various administrative records, including detailed handwritten notes for an undated national conference note: first box in CS aisle 13; note: 57th box, 1982-1990 (Box 30)
  - Records: various DSOC records, 1979-84, including staff meetings notes, staff search file, mailing lists; issues of the Discussion Bulletin and Socialist Forum; the remainin quarter of the box contains NAM Discussion Bulletins, and a file of various administrative materials., 1979-1984 (Box 30A)
  - Records: DSOC Youth Section, principally conference materials, 1979-83., 1979-1983 (Box 31)
  - Records: about half the box concerns the 1989 Convention; Youth Section records, 1979-83, including correspondence, Office Committe, and conferences comprise the rest of the box, along with several issues of Socialist Forum., 1979-1989 (Box 32)
  - Records: New American Movement, 1970s-early 1980s, including conventions, locals, publications and reports, and one file of DSA 1989 Convention minutes., 1970s-1989 (Box 32A)
  - Records: Youth Section Executive Committee minutes, 1989; Key Lists; one thick file on North Shore (NY) chapter of Mobilization for Survival, 1988-1992 (Box 33)
  - Records: Correspondence, 1979; Topical and activities files, 1980s; some Youth Section records, 1979-1990 (Box 33A)
  - Records: Socialist International and DSOC, including correspondence, with the SI and its constitutent members, some of which is Michael Harrington's, and various reports, position papers, etc., 1974-1982 (Box 34)
  - Records: about half the box consists of 1983 Convention (Detroit) materials; New Directions caucus; some materials on joint DSOC/NAM letterhead; various administrative records as recent as 1992; several files of materials accumulated or created by Saul Wellman, former Communist active in Washington DC / Maryland chapters., 1983-1992 (Box 34A)
  - Records: New American Movement, 1970s: chapters, mailings, conferences, reports from organizers, 1970-1979 (Box 35)
  - Records: Conventions, 1980, 1983, 1985; NAM convention, 1978; one file, DOSC/Left Unity, 1978-80, 1977-1985 (Box 35A)
  - Records: New American Movement, 1977-82: topical and activity files, with some administrative files; contains circulars, correspondence, reports, publications, etc., 1977-1982 (Box 36)
  - Records: DSOC/DSA, NAM: DSA 1983 convention; DSOC minutes--nat'l Board, National Interim Committee, 1981-82; includes discussion of merger with NAM; also various topical files and adminsitive materials, including reports; NAM: discussion of, and conflict over merger with DSOC, Bulk, 1979-1982 19762-1986, bulk 1979-1982; 1979-1982 (Box 37)
  - Records: Key Lists, 1982-87; Michael Harrington engagements, 1985-87, i.e., speaking tours, mostly administrative correspondence and related materials, with little or no MH correspondence, 1982-1987 (Box 38)
  - Records: Michael Harrington speaking engagements, travell including datebooks, letters to MH, logistics and finances, 1983-89; the remaining third of the box contains National Interim Committee minutes and related documents, 1982-87., 1982-1989 (Box 39)
  - Records: States and Chapters, Kentucky--New York; Youth Section files, including Executive Committee, National Office Committee, 1985-87, correspondence, and a 1982 conference; a thick file on anti-draft activity, mainly Committee Against Registration and the Draft; DSA 1983 convention ballots, 1980-1983 (Box 40)
  - Records: about half the box is devoted to the 1980 NYC Mobilization Against the Draft demonstration; some Executive Committee minutes, 1986-87; Staff Meetings, 1982; Key Lists; one thick file "Transitional Economic Program," Socialist International file with letters to Harrington, 1985-86, and from the same date span, a file of letters to Harrington marked "pending, hold", 1980-1987 (Box 41)
  - Records: DSOC early years, 1972-75, resolutions, minutes, correspondence a folder of National Interim Committee biographies, circular letters: DSA 1986-87, circular letters (a few from Harrington), correspondence, minutes, reports, etc.; a few files on the New American Movement, mostly on its founding, 1972; a 1974 organizational perspective document by Bodgan Denitch., 1972-1987 (Box 42)
  - Records: Audiotapes (36): including League for Industrial Democracy/Young Peoples Socialist League Christmas Conference, 1970 (approx 18 tapes); Labor Institute Conference, April 1968 (approx 11 tapes); N. Hill, Michael Harrington, six tapes, undated., 1968, 1970, undated (Box 43)
  - Records: about half the box is devoted to the 1980 Mobilization Against the Draft demonstration; much of the remainder consists of several files of what appear to be Mobilization for Survival records, including its Religious Task Force and Gay Task Force; also materials from a 1980 conference., 1979-1980 (Box 44)
  - Records: Naational Executive Committee files, 1982-88; staff meeting notes; files on peace movement activity, including Pro-Lifers for Survival; Institute for Democratic Socialism (two thick files, ca. 1980-82), 1980-1988 (Box 45)
  - Records: the bulk of the box is concerned with a DSA sponsored 1980 conference on Eurosocialism, and includes some Harrington correspondence, including a letter to Francois Mitterand (in French) in the "Keynoters" file; there are also several DSA Feminist Commission files; there are also several files on an early 1980s membership recruitment campaign, 1980-1988 (Box 46)
  - Records: Eurosocialism conference, including three-ring binder with conference materials, also, thank you letters, some from Harrington; 1978 event celebrating Harrington's 50th birthday; Debs-Thomas dinner, 1975; miscellaneous DSOC administrative materials, 1975-1980 (Box 47)
  - Records: bulk of box contains membership files, including questionnaires and a NYC membership map; a file on 1987 convention delegates; Esecutive Committee minutes, 1990-93; Newsletter files; topical and event files., 1984-1993 (Box 48)
  - Records: Young Socialist Alliance; University activism; anti-racism activism; msicellaneous topical and administrative files, 1977-ca. 1987 (Box 49)
  - Records: Justice For All files, 1987 (anti-poverty, economic justice); 1981 dinner honoring Willy Brandt; peace and disarmament files; several Mobilization for Survival records files, ca. 1980-ca. 1987 (Box 50)
  - Records: several Justice for All files; various administrative records, including some correspondence re Harrington speaking engagements; thick file of resumes for an unidentified position; topical files, most concerned with poverty, inequality, etc., 1980s (Box 51)
  - Records: about half of the box contains 1983 DSA internal documents from various policy discussions, retreats, etc.; one thick file of correspondence, 1983-84; correspondence with local DSOC organizations, 1976-79, 1976-1985 (Box 52)
  - Records: bulk of box is Justice for All files, including circular letters from Harrington, 1987; also National Executive Committee minutes, 1984; correspondence with local DSOC groups, 1979-80; Feminits Commission directory, undated; various topical and administrative files., 1979-1987 (Box 53)
  - Records: bulk concerns 1985 convention, including membership and delegate information; one file of correspondence of Bill Spence (Youth Section), 1986; Feminist Commission file, 1984-1988 (Box 54)
  - Records: 1980s files on black liberation, Native Americans, prisons and political prisoners; Hunter college NYC student activism file, 1989; files on other organizations, including the John Brown Anti-Klan Committee, ca. 1980-ca. 1989 (Box 55)
  - Records: Executive Director Maxine Phillips correspondence, 1983-84; Democratic Agenda conference, 1979, Washington, DC; Democratic Left correspondence, and other DA materials; 1986 DSA office opening gala; miscellaneous topical files and administrative materials, 1979-1986 (Box 56)
  - Records: National Executive Committe, 1982-86; Religious Caucus, New Directions Caucus; Tribute to Moe Foner, 1981; files related to 1988 Democratic Party events; several state and local chapter files., 1980-1989 (Box 57)
  - Records: Contains files, mostly 1980s, on international solidarity, pro-democracy struggles, e.g., Central America, East Timor, Northern Ireland, anti-Gulf War, and draft resistance, 1980., 1978-1991 (Box 58)
  - Records: National Mobilization Against the Draft (March 22, 1980 demonstration); several anti-nuclear weapons files, 1978-79, 1978-1980 (Box 59)
  - Records: American Solidarity Movement (with labor, also voter registration, early 1980s); Feminist Commission, Structure Committee Report, 1982-83; Justice for All Campaign (anti-poverty, early 1980s); Poverty Conference Proposal, by Harrington, 1984; Poverty correspondence, Harrington, 1987; DSA renewal campaigns, 1982-83, 1980-1987 (Box 60)
  - Records: NYC DSA, including executive committee minutes, cadre lists, early 1980s; National Office Communications, 1979-80; Economic policy reports and comments thereon; Reproductive rights, 1979-1985 (Box 61)
  - Records: "Political Cases", some re government surveillance and rights of givernment employees; notable names include Ron Dellums, Jane Fonda, Black Panther Party, Peter Boehmer vs. Nixon; 1970s, 1974-1975 (Box 62)
  - Records: DSOC-DSA, DSA Youth section, 1982-88; a miscellany of administrative records and topical files; includes a folder of Central America correspondence with a few Harrington items; a number of the files are from the NYC DSA chapter, 1982-1988 (Box 63)
  - Records: Student Peace Mobilization Project folder, 1980-82, with some Harrington letters; International Union of Socialist Youth, early 1980s reports, etc.; Institute for Democratic Socialism Youth Conference, 1979; Youth Organizing Fund, 1979; DSA Summer Conference, 1983, 1979-1984 (Box 64)
  - Records: Youth Conference, 1982; Democratic Left Advisory Committee, 1984; various DSA committees: Restructuring, Finance; National Executive Committee, mid-1980s; Speaking Tours/Bureau 1990; clippngs on DSA and for Harrington, 1980s, 1982-1990 (Box 65)
  - Records: Rainbow Coalition, 1987-88; DSA Health Project, 1991-92; Women's March, 1992; Democratic Left; natioanl Offce: circulars, reports; Electoral Action Task Force; Speaking tours; Correspondence with New Democratic Party (Canada), 1987-1993 (Box 66)
  - Records: DSOC meetings and conventions, 1973-76; Democratic Party work, including campaign to Make harrington a delegate to convention; "[Pete] Hammill/Harrington" folder (clippings); Socialist Scholars Conference, 1992; Sherri Levine Correspondence, 1987, Education Director' folder "Harrington, Government Spying On., 1973-1992 (Box 67)
  - Records: DSOC letter 1970s-early 1980s topical files: peace, anti-nuclear, energy conservation, others; National Student Peace Day, 1984, ca. 1976-1984 (Box 68)
  - Records: Youth Section, including correspondence, Jeremy Karpatkin, Nat'l Organizer; Chapter Repors; National Student Peace Day; New Jersey and NYC YS chapters; Central America, 1980-1985 (Box 69)
  - Records: One file of Harrington correspondence, 1987; Miwcellaneous topical and administrative files, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 70)
  - Records: Democratic Party Convention (1988) DSA activity; one file, DP 1984 convention, 1984, 1988 (Box 71)
  - Records: Youth Section, 1987, several files; bulk of box consists of reference material-- "white papers", reports, and some like DSA materials, 1981-1987 (Box 72)
  - Records: About half of the box is Youth Section materials from the latter 1980s, including the Hiring Ctte for a nat'l Director, 1987; YS conference, 1993; DSA: North Carolina meeting, 1988, some national office records, including correspondence of director Michael Lighty., 1987-1993 (Box 73)
  - Records: DSA Conventions, 1995, 1997; "DSA Mission" folder; Chapter files (MD, Northern VA, Pittsburgh, Sacramento, etc.); Nationasl Executive Committee resolution, 1981-88; National Board Resolutions, 1981-1998 (Box 74)
  - Records: 1995 convention; Structure Committee; National Political Committee, including minutes notebook; Organizing Manual; Local Sruvey returns, 1991; Reports and other writings, some annotated, 1991-1995 (Box 75)